Guide to the Thomas Raynesford Lounsbury Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, Series I
  - Wells, Horace Lemuel, 1891 (Box 24, Folder 497)
  - Welsh, Charles, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 497)
  - Wenborne, Charles A., 1905 (Box 24, Folder 497)
  - Wendell, Barrett, 1909 (Box 24, Folder 497)
  - Wentworth, Elinor E., 1893 (Box 24, Folder 497)
  - West, A. G., 1899 (Box 24, Folder 498)
  - West, Andrew Fleming, 1896, 1909 (Box 24, Folder 498)
  - Westervelt, Alice, 1892-1904 (Box 24, Folder 498)
  - Weston, S. Burns, 1906-1907 (Box 24, Folder 498)
  - Wheaton, Frank Woodruff, 1896 (Box 24, Folder 498)
  - Wheeler, Albert S.(*), 1865-1898 (Box 24, Folder 499)
  - Wheeler, Alexander, 1898-1899 (Box 24, Folder 500)
  - Wheeler, Benjamin, 1895-1903 (Box 24, Folder 500)
  - Wheeler, Edwin, S., 1886-1906 (Box 24, Folder 500)
  - Wheeler, Harriet A., 1896 (Box 24, Folder 501)
  - Wheeler, Jane M., 1909 (Box 24, Folder 501)
  - Wheeler, John Davenport, undated (Box 24, Folder 501)
  - Whipple, Carolyn Shipman (Mrs. Frank B.), 1906 (Box 24, Folder 501)
  - Whipple, Edwin P., 1880 (Box 24, Folder 501)
  - White, Andrew Dickson, 1895-1910 (Box 24, Folder 501)
  - White, Henry, 1902 (Box 24, Folder 501)
  - White, Henry Charles, 1891-1892 (Box 24, Folder 502)
  - White, James William, 1892-1907 (Box 24, Folder 502)
  - White, John Stuart, 1903 (Box 24, Folder 502)
  - White, Lucy Schwab, undated (Box 24, Folder 502)
  - White, William Augustus, 1902-1914 (Box 24, Folder 502)
  - Whitfield, Erle W., 1911 (Box 24, Folder 503)
  - Whiting, Sarah F., 1883 (Box 24, Folder 503)
  - Whitney, Elizabeth B., 1879-1898, undated (Box 24, Folder 503)
  - Whitney, Emily Henrietta, 1887-1904 (Box 24, Folder 504)
  - Whitney, Mrs. George Morton, 1913 (Box 24, Folder 504)
  - Whitney, Joseph Ernest, 1889 (Box 24, Folder 504)
  - Whitney, Josepha, 1911 (Box 24, Folder 504)
  - Whitney, Livingston, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 504)
  - Whitney, Margaret Dwight, 1898-1913 (Box 24, Folder 505)
  - Whitney, Marian P., 1881, undated (Box 24, Folder 505)
  - Whitney, William, 1876 (Box 24, Folder 505)
  - Whitney, William Dwight(*), 1876-1892 (Box 24, Folder 506)
  - Whittemore, Julia S., 1899 (Box 24, Folder 506)
  - Whittington, W., 1909 (Box 24, Folder 506)
  - Whyte, Arthur James, 1913 (Box 24, Folder 506)
  - Wiggin, W. H., 1906 (Box 24, Folder 507)
  - Wilcox, Asher Henry, 1911-1913 (Box 24, Folder 507)
  - Wilcox, Julius, 1885 (Box 24, Folder 507)
  - Wilder, Elizabeth, 1912 (Box 24, Folder 507)
  - Wilder, Ira H., 1891 (Box 24, Folder 507)
  - Wildman, Clara Augusta, 1897 (Box 24, Folder 507)
  - Williams, Aras James, 1891 (Box 24, Folder 508)
  - Williams, Charles Mallory, 1912 (Box 24, Folder 508)
  - Williams, Charles O., 1893-1895 (Box 24, Folder 508)
  - Williams, Frances Wayland, 1911-1913 (Box 24, Folder 508)
  - Williams, Frederick Wells, 1911 (Box 24, Folder 509)
  - Williams, George, 1894 (Box 24, Folder 509)
  - Williams, Jessie Lynch, 1912 (Box 24, Folder 509)
  - Willis, James Florence, 1897 (Box 24, Folder 509)
  - Wilson, Caroline C.(*), 1872-1914 (Box 24, Folder 510)
  - Wilson, Edmund Beecher, 1896 (Box 24, Folder 510)
  - Wilson, Francis(*), 1896-1906 (Box 24, Folder 511)
  - Wilson, John N.(*), 1872-1889 (Box 24, Folder 512)
  - Wilson, Joseph W., 1872 (Box 25, Folder 513)
  - Wilson, Lorenzo S., 1872-1878 (Box 25, Folder 513)
  - Wilson, Louis B., 1893 (Box 25, Folder 513)
  - Wilson, Willa E., 1905 (Box 25, Folder 513)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 1896-1906 (Box 25, Folder 514)
  - Winas, Fred H., 1904 (Box 25, Folder 515)
  - Winchell, Samuel R., 1884 (Box 25, Folder 515)
  - Winchester, Caleb T., 1877-1896 (Box 25, Folder 515)
  - Wingate, Charles E. L., 1893 (Box 25, Folder 515)
  - Winsor, Justin, 1882-1896 (Box 25, Folder 515)
  - Winter, Wallace C., 1905 (Box 25, Folder 516)
  - Winter, William, 1901-1902 (Box 25, Folder 516)
  - Winthrop, Buchanan, 1893 (Box 25, Folder 516)
  - Wise, Henry, 1905 (Box 25, Folder 516)
  - Wise, Thomas, 1913 (Box 25, Folder 516)
  - Wolcott, Mrs., undated (Box 25, Folder 516)
  - Wood, Katharine B.(*), 1886-1893 (Box 25, Folder 517)
  - Woodberry, George Edward(*), 1884-1905 (Box 25, Folder 518)
  - Woodford, Arthur Burnham(*), 1883-1896 (Box 25, Folder 519)
  - Woods, Katharine, 1910 (Box 25, Folder 520)
  - Woods, W. H., 1907 (Box 25, Folder 520)
  - Woodward, Benjamin W., 1892 (Box 25, Folder 520)
  - Woodward, Robert Simpson, 1905-1913 (Box 25, Folder 520)
  - Woodward, Samuel C., 1909 (Box 25, Folder 520)
  - Woodworth, C. P., 1899 (Box 25, Folder 521)
  - Woolsey, Edith, 1901 (Box 25, Folder 521)
  - Woolsey, Theodore Dwight, 1859, 1882 (Box 25, Folder 521)
  - Woolsey, Theodore Salisbury, 1884, undated (Box 25, Folder 521)
  - Worthington, D. Dulany, 1874 (Box 25, Folder 521)
  - Worthington, John(*), 1907-1908 (Box 25, Folder 522)
  - Worthington, N. B., 1873 (Box 25, Folder 523)
  - Worthington, R., 1876-1878 (Box 25, Folder 523)
  - Wright, Arthur Williams, 1873-1911 (Box 25, Folder 523)
  - Wright, Henry Parks, 1895 (Box 25, Folder 523)
  - Wright, Joseph, 1895-1904 (Box 25, Folder 523)
  - Wurts, Martha, undated (Box 25, Folder 523)
  - Wyckoff, W. K., 1883 (Box 25, Folder 523)
  - Yale Alumni Weekly
    See: Lewis Sheldon Welch, box 24, folder 496
  - Yale Banner
    See: Scott Hurtt Paradise, box 16, folder 348
  - Yale Modern Language Club, 1907 (Box 25, Folder 523)
  - Yale University Press
    See: George Parmly Day, box 4, folder 109 See: E. Byrne Hackett, box 8, folder 194
  - Yale University Treasurer's Office, 1906 (Box 25, Folder 523)
  - Yard, Robert Sterling, 1914 (Box 25, Folder 524)
  - Yeatman, Thomas, 1897-1906 (Box 25, Folder 524)
  - Yost, Caspar, 1912 (Box 25, Folder 524)
  - Young, Mason, 1873-1895 (Box 25, Folder 524)
  - Youth's Companion
    See: William Henry Rideing, box 18, folder 381
  - Zerwick, Clinton, 1905 (Box 25, Folder 524)
  - Miscellaneous, 1857-1912, undated (Box 25, Folder 525)
  - Correspondence of others (Box 25, Folder 526)
    - Beecher, ____, 1900 (Box 25, Folder 526)
    - Brush, George Jarvis(*), 1871-1893, undated (Box 25, Folder 526)
    - Chittenden, Russell Henry, undated (Box 25, Folder 526)
    - Dexter, Franklin, 1873-1875, 1905-1907 (Box 25, Folder 526)
    - Farnam, Susan Strong, 1894 (Box 25, Folder 526)
    - Furnivall, F. J., 1879 (Box 25, Folder 526)
    - Phelps, William Lyon, 1911 (Box 25, Folder 526)
    - Piaget, Louis A., 1908 (Box 25, Folder 526)
    - Warner, Charles Dudley, undated (Box 25, Folder 526)
    - Whitney, William Dwight, 1881-1884 (Box 25, Folder 526)
- Diaries and Personal Papers, Series II
  - Diaries, with notes, grades, accounts, 1856-1857, 1859 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Diaries, with speech, review, 1858-1859, 1862 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Diaries, 1878-1879, 1883, 1892, 1894-1904 (Box 26, Folder 3-7)
  - Diaries, 1905-1915 (Box 27, Folder 8-11)
  - Items removed from diaries, 1896-1915 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Commonplace book, [ca. 1853-1855], [ca. 1857-1859] (Box 27, Folder 13-14)
  - Copies of letters, notes on writers (especially Byron), record of letters sent and received, accounts, books ordered for Sheffield Scientific School library., [ca. 1871-1880] (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Addresses, accounts, record of letters sent and received, books ordered for Sheffield Scientific School library, [ca. 1878-1905] (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Address book; account books, one re: encyclopedia articles and Sheffield Scientific School library, undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Legal and financial papers, 1829, 1872-1914 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Autographs, calling cards, memorabilia, 1884, 1909, undated (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Engravings of Thomas R. Lounsbury, 1859 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Photograph of Jennie Dungan(Folwell)Lounsbury, [ca. 1871-1875] (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Photograph of unidentified woman, 1889 (Box 28, Folder 20)
- Writings, Series III
  - Fiction, undated
    - Amaryllis in the Shade: A Summer Idyl (Box 29, Folder 21-24)
    - Fairview (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Fairview (Box 30, Folder 26-28)
    - The Runaway Express Train (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - A Speculative Enterprise (Box 30, Folder 30-31)
    - Civil War novel (Box 31, Folder 32-36)
    - Unidentified (Box 31, Folder 37)
    - Unidentified (Box 32, Folder 38-41)
    - Unidentified (Box 33, Folder 42-45)
  - Poetry, undated
    - Poetry (Box 34, Folder 46)
  - English Language, undated
    - re: History of English Language (Box 34, Folder 47)
    - re: Americanisms (Box 34, Folder 48-49)
    - re: spelling (Box 34, Folder 50-51)
    - re: parts of speech (Box 35, Folder 52)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 35, Folder 53)
  - English Literature, undated
    - Early to 16th century (Box 35, Folder 54)
    - 17th century (Box 35, Folder 55)
    - 18th century (Box 35, Folder 56)
    - 19th century (Box 35, Folder 57-58)
    - Chaucer (Box 36, Folder 59)
    - Tennyson (Box 36, Folder 60-64)
    - Brownings (Box 37, Folder 65-67)
    - Campbell (Box 37, Folder 68)
    - Macaulay (Box 37, Folder 69)
    - Theater (Box 37, Folder 70)
    - Magazines (Box 37, Folder 71)
    - Copyright law (Box 37, Folder 72)
    - Copyright law (Box 38, Folder 73)
    - General (Box 38, Folder 74)
  - Miscellaneous
    - re: education and college life, undated (Box 38, Folder 75-76)
    - Speeches re: Simplified Spelling Board, 1908-1909, undated (Box 38, Folder 77)
    - Speeches: Yale, miscellaneous, undated (Box 38, Folder 78)
    - re: Sheffield Scientific School, undated (Box 38, Folder 79)
    - re: Civil War, 1864, undated (Box 38, Folder 80)
    - "The Failure of Representative Government", undated (Box 38, Folder 81)
    - "Modern Rome", undated (Box 38, Folder 82)
    - Published articles and reviews: scrapbook of clippings, [ca. 1866-1878], 1893 (Box 39, Folder 83)
    - Miscellaneous, 1898, undated (Box 39, Folder 84)
    - Unidentified fragments, undated (Box 39, Folder 85-87)
- Notes and Printed Matter, Series IV
  - English Language
    - Notes on words, undated (Box 40, Folder 88-93)
    - Notes on words: note cards, undated (Box 41–43)
    - Spelling, undated (Box 44, Folder 94)
    - Spelling: printed matter, 1865-1908, undated (Box 44, Folder 95-96)
    - Americanisms, undated (Box 44, Folder 97-98)
    - Index of words and names; miscellaneous, undated (Box 44, Folder 99)
  - English Literature
    - Chronology, undated
      - 1740-1752 (Box 45, Folder 100-103)
      - 1753 (Box 46, Folder 104)
      - 1838 (Box 46, Folder 105)
    - Early to 16th century, undated (Box 46, Folder 106)
    - 17th century, undated (Box 47, Folder 107)
    - 18th century, undated (Box 47, Folder 108-109)
    - 19th century, undated (Box 47, Folder 110-113)
    - Chaucer, 1876-1888, undated (Box 48, Folder 114)
    - Jonson, undated (Box 48, Folder 115)
    - Southey, undated (Box 48, Folder 116)
    - Shelley, undated (Box 48, Folder 117)
    - Shelley: printed matter, mostly re: The Shelley Society, 1886-1889 (Box 48, Folder 118)
    - Tennyson, undated (Box 48, Folder 119)
    - Alphabetical file, undated (Box 48, Folder 119)
    - A - F (Box 48, Folder 120)
    - G - P (Box 48, Folder 121)
    - R - Y (Box 48, Folder 122)
    - Theater, undated (Box 49, Folder 123)
    - Poetry: notes and transcribed poems, undated (Box 49, Folder 124)
    - Magazines, undated (Box 49, Folder 125)
    - Copyright law: notes, transcribed letters printed matter, undated (Box 49, Folder 126)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 49, Folder 127)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Short notes, aphorisms, witticisms, undated (Box 49, Folder 128-129)
    - Other literatures, undated (Box 50, Folder 130)
    - Cooper, undated (Box 50, Folder 131)
    - Examination questions, 1879-1887, undated (Box 50, Folder 132)
    - Notes on grades, [1903?], [1915?] (Box 50, Folder 132)
    - Examination papers: Henry W. Farnam, Vance C. McCormick, undated (Box 50, Folder 132)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 50, Folder 133)
    - Unidentified fragments, undated (Box 50, Folder 134)
    - Scrapbooks of clippings, [ca. 1850s-1860s] (Box 50, Folder 135-136)
    - Scrapbook of clippings, [ca. 1860s-1870s] (Box 51, Folder 137)
    - Call slips from British Museum, 1879, 1892, undated (Box 51, Folder 138)
    - Miscellaneous printed matter, 1878-1914, undated (Box 51, Folder 139)